JITENDRA GARG

ENGINEERING MANAGER | PROJECT MANAGER | SCRUM MASTER

BANGALORE, INDIA 560059 - +91 - 8277433277

jitendragarg@gmail.com - contact@jitendragarg.com - www.jitendragarg.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have 14+ years of IT industry experience and **7+ years of experience in project management**. I have played multiple roles related to technical delivery in multiple domains while working on over 20+ technologies. I am currently focused on continuous improvement and agile project management. I am looking for a role allowing me to use the full gamut of my technical skills and my coaching and mentoring experience.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Technical Delivery - Able to deliver IT software and hardware products, keeping up with market trends

- Delivered 3-5 projects simultaneously while exceeding quality expectations of the customer
- Completed projects in multiple technologies including machine learning and blockchain
- Achieved 90% success rate over 7+ years delivering 30+ projects ahead of schedule

Team Growth - Promoting continuous improvement and continuous learning

- Implemented up-skilling plans and promoted regular coaching and mentoring
- Acted as mentor and training manager for colleagues at both junior and senior level
- Championed and supported agile values advancing organizational agility

Stakeholder Engagement - Able to manage multiple stakeholders from multiple backgrounds

- Engaged with C-level executives working closely to reach organizational goals.
- Experienced in working in conjunction with customer to improve the feedback cycle
- Pursued continuous involvement of stakeholders during project execution phase

Delivery Process Optimization - Capable of using industry standard practices to improve delivery

- Coached senior management including C-level executives on code quality standards
- Improved business process of end customer using Lean principles to reduce waste
- Prepared and enacted contingency plan, business continuation plan, and IT service roadmap.

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Planning - Delivery Planning, Effort and Cost Estimation, Risk Mitigation Planning, Resource Planning

Delivery - Technical Delivery Management, Stakeholder Management

Team - Up-skilling, Hiring Management, Technical Training, Conflict Management, Coaching

Framework - SCRUM, Waterfall, Kanban, Lean, XP

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master 1 by Scrum.org

Scrum Foundations Professional Certificate by CertiProf

Power Platform Fundamentals by Microsoft

Academic English Proficiency Level 8.0 by IELTS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Primary Language - C#, ASP.Net, WCF, Web Api 2, HTML5, Javascript, Jquery, PowerApps

Cloud Services - Azure IaaS, Azure PaaS, Azure Machine Learning, Azure IoT, Google Domains

Tools - Visual Studio, VS Code, SQL Server, Jira, Postman, TFS, Sonarqube, Jenkins, Git, Trello, Slack

Others - ASP.Net MVC, WPF, VB.Net, Winforms, Windows Service, CSS3, Solidity, .Net Core, MS Dynamics 365, Wordpress, Flutter.js, Angular 2, PowerBI, Power Automate, OpenAI, React.js

EDUCATION

MAULANA AZAD NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BHOPAL - JUNE 2003 - MAY 2007

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology - 7.58 GPA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sonata Software Limited, Bangalore - Senior Project Manager

April 2021 - April 2023

- Executed 3 to 5 projects simultaneously in varying technology stack
- Delivered multiple projects in Power Platform, Power Automate and Power BI
- Developed applications for multiple clients including Microsoft using SharePoint and Power Apps
- Acted as a liaison for Microsoft and the end customer organization

Digital Convergence Technologies, Pune - Project Manager

October 2019 - January 2020

- Executed strategies to improve technical delivery process and cut down risks by 30%
- Implemented upskilling plan to improve technical capabilities of delivery team
- Successfully delivered new features to customer in 60% of estimated effort
- Updated KRAs and KPIs to promote continuous learning and improvement

Nexshore Technologies, Bangalore - Team Leader

June 2018 - May 2019

- Won a project from Karnataka's tourism department, delivering newsworthy hardware solutions
- Delivered cloud storage solution akin Google Drive designed from scratch within 3 months
- Acted as hiring and training manager for internship program for technical colleges
- Implemented proof of concept application in Ethereum Blockchain using Azure workbench

Vidushi Software Solutions, Valsad - Technical Lead .Net

August 2017 - May 2018

- Executed Scrum at Scale and conducted Agile coaching for senior management to improve agility
- Delivered 3 products from scratch with a quality rating of A+, higher than expected B rating
- Led organization wide upskilling program to reach 30% certified employees from 2%
- Implemented proof of concept application in Machine Learning and Sharepoint

Melstar Infotech, Pune - Technical Analyst

July 2016 - January 2017

- Led a team of 20+ employees including DevOps, Business Analysts, IT and support staff
- Put contingency plans into practice to improve system availability to 99.5% from 90%
- Owned and led a major product working on transactions over 200 million USD
- Updated coaching and mentoring program, upskilling 60% employees over 3 months

AISOFT Technologies, Bangalore - Project Leader

August 2014 - December 2015

- Enacted and executed mentoring program for trainee and junior technical staff
- Provided consultation for IT service roadmap, development and release planning
- Managed outsourcing operations of Veritas Petroleum Services as account manager
- Built a team from new hires and led them to a successful delivery for a major product

HUDE Labs, Bhopal - Lead Technical Consultant

October 2012 - August 2014

- Created go-to-market strategy for multiple products including e-commerce store
- Consulted with end customers for technical delivery and release schedule planning
- Implemented industry standard code quality checks and peer review processes
- Championed UX driven design and test driven development across organization

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore - Project Engineer

July 2007 - February 2012

- Won a project from a competing vendor worth 2 million USD acting as project lead
- Automated fixes for key problem areas, freeing 40% of development effort
- Won "Key Talent" award in 2007 for performing above expectations during training
- Coached and mentored colleagues on code quality and good programming practices